Preliminary Guide to the Bradbury Thompson Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Bradbury Thompson collection
1943-1990
AOB 19
Yale University Arts Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
The Bradbury Thompson Collection consists of examples of Thompson's graphic design work including postage stamps, logos, and book, magazine, and corporate publication designs. The majority of the collection consists of Thompson designs that were a part of the Westvaco-sponsored exhibit, "Bradbury Thompson: Innovative Designer," which was exhibited at Yale's Sterling Memorial Library in 1992.
Thompson, Bradbury
Associated Materials
Bradbury Thompson Papers (MS 1794), Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Bradbury Thompson, Wetvaco Corporation and Louis Silverstein, 1980-1992.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Bradbury Thompson (1911-1995) was a graphic designer and art director who had a distinguished career in positions with the Westvaco Corporation, for whom he designed the American Classic Book Series and Westvaco Inspirations for Printers; Mademoiselle magazine; Art News; and Smithsonian magazine. He designed the limited edition Washburn College Bible, which was published by Oxford University Press in 1979, and designed over 100 United States postage stamps. He was an adjunct professor of graphic design in the Yale School of Art from 1956 to 1995. His autobiography, The Art of Graphic Design, was published by Yale University Press in 1988. He received many awards, including the American Institute of Graphic Arts gold medal for lifetime achievement.
Scope and Contents
The Bradbury Thompson Collection consists of examples of Thompson's graphic design work including postage stamps, logos, and book, magazine, and corporate publication designs. The majority of the collection consists of Thompson designs that were a part of the Westvaco-sponsored exhibit, "Bradbury Thompson: Innovative Designer," which was exhibited at Yale's Sterling Memorial Library in 1992. Many of the designs in the exhibition were from the serial publication Westvaco Inspirations for Printers. The exhibit had previously been mounted at other venues, including the Frick Gallery in Pittsburgh and the ITC Gallery in New York City.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of material.
Graphic arts; Graphic design (Typography); Thompson, Bradbury; Westvaco Corporation
- Box Listing
  - Articles, brochures, and essays about Bradbury Thompson, 1979-1989 (Box 1)
  - Thompson design examples
    - Postage stamps, 1963-1990 (Box 1)
      General note
      See also Oversize Box 6.
    - Corporate identity (logos, etc.), undated (Box 1)
    - Magazines and corporate publications, 1944-1989 (Box 1)
  - Material relating to Westvaco exhibit, "Bradbury Thompson: Innovative Designer"
    - Exhibit slides from Frick Gallery, University of Pittsburgh and ITC Gallery, International Typeface Corp., New York, undated (Box 1)
    - Extra wall and display captions (preservation photocopies), undated (Box 1)
    - Exhibition panels arranged by exhibit themes, undated
      - Exhibit sign, undated (Box 2)
      - "A Love of Books", undated (Box 2)
      - "A Love of Books," cont'd., undated (Box 3)
      - "A Fascination of Magazines", undated (Box 3)
      - "Corporate Publications", undated (Box 4)
      - "Photography and Typography", undated (Box 5)
      - "Alphabet as Graphic Design", undated (Box 5)
      - "Classic Art as Modern Graphics", undated (Box 5)
      - " Westvaco Inspirations Selections From Issues 142 to 217, 1943-1962", undated (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous corporate identity design examples, undated (Box 6)
- Oversize
  - Thompson design examples
    - Postage stamp: America's Libraries, undated (Box 6)
    - Issue of Printing News, Volume C, No. 4, January 28, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Washburn Bible presentation brochure, 1979 (Box 6)